[
    
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"During respiration exchange of gases takes place in _____.",
        "options":
        [
            "Trachea and larynx",
            "Alveoli of lungs",
            "Alveoli and throat",
            "Throat and larynx"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Alveoli of lungs"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"When a few drops of iodine solution are added to rice water, the solution turns blue- black in colour. This indicates that rice water contains:",
        "options":
        [
            "Fats",
            "Complex proteins",
            "Starch",
            "Simple proteins"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Starch"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"Glycolysis process occurs in which part of the cell?",
        "options":
        [
            "Cytoplasm",
            "Nucleus",
            "Mitochondria",
            "Chloroplast"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Cytoplasm"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"The fermentation of glucose by yeast normally yields",
        "options":
        [
            "Alcohol, CO2 and 36 ATP",
            "CO2, H20 and 36 ATP",
            "Alcohol, CO2 and 2ATP",
            "Lactic acid, CO7 and 2 ATP"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Lactic acid, CO7 and 2 ATP"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"The longest stage in the cell cycle is",
        "options":
        [
            "Interphase",
            "Anaphase",
            "Metaphase",
            "None of the Above"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Interphase"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"The spindle apparatus is formed during the ________ phase of mitosis.",
        "options":
        [
            "Telophase",
            "Metaphase",
            "Prophase",
            "Anaphase"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Metaphase"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"Nuclear DNA replicates in the ________ phase.",
        "options":
        [
            "G2 Phase",
            "M Phase",
            "S Phase",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAns": "S Phase"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"The energy currency is:",
        "options":
        [
            "DNA",
            "RNA",
            "ATP",
            "Chlorophyll"
        ],
        "correctAns": "ATP"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"ATP and NADP 2H are produced in:",
        "options":
        [
            "Mitochondria",
            "Chloroplast",
            "Peroxisomes",
            "Lysosomes"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Mitochondria"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"Cyclic chain of reactions called as",
        "options":
        [
            "Tricarboxylic acid cycle",
            "Carbon Cycle",
            "Water Cycle",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "correctAns": "tricarboxylic acid cycle"
    }
]
